<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Flora on Piedmont Prairie</title>
    <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Flora on Piedmont Prairie</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/asclepias_tuberosa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/asclepias_tuberosa/</guid>
      <description>During late Spring and early Summer, butterfly weed (Asclepias tuberosa) is a common splash of color on Piedmont roadsides and old fields. This milkweed typically only grows to a couple of feet high, unlike another Piedmont resident common milkweed (Asclepias syriaca), which reach 4-5 feet tall in unmown rights-of-way. Milkweed leaves are an important food source for caterpillars of the Monarch butterfly (Danaus plexippus). The sweet nectar of Milkweeds attracts many pollinators including bees, wasps, flies, beetles, ants, and more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/coreoposis_major/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/coreoposis_major/</guid>
      <description>Greater tickseed (Coreopsis major) and many other members of the Asteraceae are common Piedmont roadside inhabitants. This plant typically only reaches up to 3 feet in height. But with its striking, large yellow flowers, greater tickseed can stand out along roadside edges. Unlike species like Wild Quinine, the native range of Greater tickseed only extends into Louisiana and not into the Mid-West plains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/marshallia_obovata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/marshallia_obovata/</guid>
      <description>You&amp;rsquo;re unlikely to see Piedmont Barbara&amp;rsquo;s buttons (Marshallia obovata) without looking for it. This plant rarely grows more than a couple of feet high. The late Spring, white flowers do not always stand out like the yellow flowers of many Asteraceae. Visit the Piedmont habitat at the North Carolina Botanical Garden in late May though, and you&amp;rsquo;re sure to find Barbara&amp;rsquo;s buttons in bloom.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/parthenium_integrifolium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/parthenium_integrifolium/</guid>
      <description>Wild quinine (Parthenium integrifolium) is commonly found on roadsides and rights-of-way in the Piedmont. It is the most observed species in the NC Piedmont Roadside Native Plant project on iNaturalist, which has been running since 2016. This member of the Asteraceae family is not particularly showy, but it&amp;rsquo;s presence often indicates a quality habitat for other sun-loving prairie plants. The native range of wild quinine extends from the Piedmont through prairie states as far north as Minnesota.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/quercus_marilandica/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/quercus_marilandica/</guid>
      <description>Blackjack oak (Quercus marilandica) is a small tree that can thrive in poor soils. This tree&amp;rsquo;s thick bark and waxy leaves makes it tolerant of fire. Blackjack oak and other fire-resistant trees are often associated with open, savanna habitat. The Southern Piedmont Pine-Oak Savannas project has documented over 800 species of plants found in these open habitats.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/schizachyrium_scoparium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/schizachyrium_scoparium/</guid>
      <description>Along with big bluestem and indiangrass, little bluestem is a characteristic species of the tallgrass prairie. However, its range extends well beyond the Midwestern prairies and is found throughout the Piedmont and Eastern United States. Little bluestem is the larval host for several insects, including many skippers, a family of butterflies. The grass forms bunches whose subtle bluish hue can give Piedmont old fields a ocean-like feel in midsummer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/sorghastrum_nutans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/sorghastrum_nutans/</guid>
      <description>Like little bluestem, indiangrass (Sorghastrum nutans) is characteristic tallgrass prairie grass also common in the Piedmont. Where indiangrass has formed large colonies, the seed heads provide stunning visual interest to roadsides in the Fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/symphyotrichum_grandiflorum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://piedmontprairie.us/plants/symphyotrichum_grandiflorum/</guid>
      <description>There are many asters native to the Piedmont Prairie, but largeflower aster (Symphyotrichum grandiflorum) is endemic to the Piedmont and parts of the Coastal Plain. This plant can be prolific with its purple flowers, making it easy to spot for the keen eye when it blooms in early Fall. This species is listed as vulnerable by the North Carolina Natural Heritage Program.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
